A party?
There's a party to celebrate the
appointment of a new Highlander emissary,
and they've asked that
you and Rafinha attend.
It was Brother Raf who
sent that message, right?
But why us?
He said if I told you to bring Lyn,
you'd understand.
What does that mean?
I don't know...
Um, why am I here?
Because you're going to the party too.
Liselotte's father, the chancellor,
will also be in attendance.
I told him I'm bringing a friend.
B-But I...
Come with us, Leone!
Okay.
Thanks, Liselotte.
Okay, next stop: shopping for party dresses!
Reborn
to Master the Blade
From Hero-King to Extraordinary Squire
If we're going to a party,
we'll need dresses!
Episode 7    The Hyral Menas's Disease
You don't need to buy a dress for me too...
It's fine!
Brother Raf will pay for it all!
Sounds good to me.
Magicite beasts!
Eris!
You guys...
Where are the magicite beasts?
It's fine. I defeated them all.
Is that... a humanoid?
Does that mean it used to be a Highlander?
No, it was a demihuman magicite beast.
Demihumans are affected by the Prism Flow.
But I'm a Hyral Menas, so I'm fine.
Um, Ripple... are you all right?
You look kind of unwell.
I'm fine, I'm fine.
Just a little dizzy. I'm feeling just fine!
The same thing happened last time, though.
Last time?
We've been through this several times
since returning to the capital.
We've seen magicite beasts
appear out of nowhere.
And then Ripple ends up feeling sick.
I don't know why.
I'll be just fine soon. It's okay.
You think it's the Bloodchain Brigade that
are making the magicite beasts appear?
I don't know.
We'll have to have the new
emissary look into it.
What's this?
The money for tailoring your dresses.
Rafael had a sudden mission to deal with,
so he couldn't come.
That's why we came to give you this instead.
Thank you!
Thanks for coming all this way!
It's fine! But in exchange,
let us come shopping with you.
Several Days Later
We're almost out of time.
Will you need much longer?
All set!
You look great!
You're gorgeous!
This is great! It's fantastic!
Yup.
I like how cute you are when
you get excited over yourself!
That's rare...
I'm hungry.
That's right.
We wanted to leave room for all the good food
at the party, so we haven't eaten anything...
Negotiations?
Yes. To see if we can get
the latest equipment.
It's a good chance to ask
the emissary directly.
But will they say yes, you think?
I actually know the emissary.
I stayed with him when I was on
an exchange program in the Highland.
An exchange program in the Highland?
I had no idea there was such a thing!
It was somewhat of a special case.
When Prince Wein was there on exchange,
I went as his bodyguard.
Ma'am, would you ask the emissary
if he has any information
on the Bloodchain Brigade?
Yeah, he might know something.
And it'd be great if he knew anything
about the man in the black mask.
That could be difficult.
He might be willing to talk to the knights,
but not to a bunch of academy students.
Oh... Yeah, that's right.
Let's find information on the
Bloodchain Brigade ourselves.
I'll help.
We mustn't rush things carelessly.
Thanks, everyone.
I'm so hungry!
Let's hurry up and go inside, Chris!
Rani, if you run in that dress...
You'll trip.
Why didn't you say so sooner?
You okay?
Are you hurt?
You mustn't cause trouble for Chris.
Brother!
Chris, I'm sorry she's such a handful.
Thanks for always being there for her...
Not at all. She's always
been there for me, too.
Is something wrong, Cousin?
I was just thinking that this is the
first time I've seen you in a dress.
You're really pretty.
Thank you.
Rani helped me out.
Right?
I'm pretty confident in my choice this time!
And um... I guess you brought Lyn, too.
Oh! Brother, you were just
looking at her breasts!
I know it's just something men
instinctively do around women,
but to be honest, being looked at that way...
S-Sorry! I was just wondering
where Lyn was...
What's wrong?
We're hungry. We haven't eaten all day.
We heard we could get good food here.
Then let's talk later. Shall we head inside?
Let's!
Yes, please take them inside, Sir Rafael.
The noise is so loud that the guests
might think all of us are starving.
I'll go say hello to my father...
Bye!
See you later!
Did you see that girl? She's gorgeous!
She's as pretty as a doll...
I can't take my eyes off her!
Wh-What?
Their stomachs are growling?
Sorry! I've been so busy
that I haven't had time to eat!
Brother's so nice! I love him!
Thank you, my dear cousin!
Okay, go ahead and eat!
Yes!
Chris, let's eat!
Yes, let's!
Magicite beasts? Here?!
My meat!
What a surprise!
No fair, Chris!
Don't worry, I got you some too.
When did she...
Way to go, Chris!
Some of the tables are still intact.
Let's fight to protect our food!
Protect the people, not the food!
Well, it's all the same in the end, right?
Aether Pierce!
Chris, get back!
He's fast.
His strength, speed, and technique...
They're all on an entirely different level.
He's been no slouch
when it comes to practicing!
I hope you're all unharmed?
Wow, Brother!
You're the only person besides Chris
who moves too fast for me to see!
That slash on the fifth attack
and thrust on the seventeenth
were especially well executed, Cousin Raf!
You saw the whole thing, Inglis?
Yup! There were twenty-one attacks in all!
Hey, how many did you see, Rafinha?
Maybe you didn't need my help.
Just the first two or three.
It's just habit, though, you know.
I'm glad it's not just me.
No, it was wonderful to see!
I'd love to challenge you to a duel soon!
Holding nothing back!
Well, I wouldn't want you to get hurt...
I guess we could do a
practice fight, though...
What would get him to fight me
at full strength?
Rafael, leave this room to them,
and hurry to Prince Wein
and Emissary Theodore!
All right.
Rani, Chris, Leone.
Keep the people here safe.
Okay, Brother!
Got it!
Leave it to us!
Here you go, everyone.
I was looking forward to
wearing these dresses,
but I guess we're doing the
same thing we always do.
No kidding. They could've let us have
the day off to have some fun...
I am having fun!
I love fighting magicite beasts!
Chris is special!
She's a wild animal in a dress!
That's right!
How rude. I'm going
to fight elegantly today.
Is the fact that they're not scared
in a situation like this
a sign that they'll make good knights?
Like a proper lady.
Observe!
See? Very elegant!
Yes, but...
You're taking them down so easily that
you're actually more scary than usual.
Yes, it's a little too easy.
But I don't want to mess up my dress.
Oh, you guys finish them off.
I know!
Chris! They're coming!
From over here, too!
They're fast!
I suppose one finger is too slow.
In which case...
Yes! It worked!
What? With both hands?!
Check this out, Rani!
That was a good fight, huh?
I'm glad you had fun!
I was enjoying myself so much,
I went a little overboard.
It was more than a little, I thought.
Ma'am, we beat the magicite beasts,
which means we can eat now, right?
Right?
You two...
Sure, in moderation.
I'll go finish them off while
you replenish your strength.
Thank you!
Leone! Principal Miliera!
You're safe!
Yes. So's my father.
But...
Huh?
Where are Inglis and Rafinha?
Oh, it's Liselotte!
Hey there!
I have no idea what you're saying.
Anyway, come with me!
Something's wrong with Ripple.
Brother Rafael!
Looks like you finished up.
Which means our only remaining problem is...
What is that?
The space around her is distorted?
Is that awful-looking light what
summoned the magicite beasts?
Yes, she suddenly collapsed, and...
We defeated the magicite beasts,
but I don't know what's going on...
So that Hyral Menas summoned
magicite beasts to make them attack us!
No, Ripple wouldn't do that!
Eris and the other Hyral Menases
have worked so hard to protect
this country and its people!
You can't trust them, even after that?
Of course, we know that.
You're right, but...
Don't be angry at them.
They have a duty to be ready for danger.
O-Okay...
Any idea what could have
caused this, Theodore?
Highland Emissary Theodore
It's hard to say for sure,
but it may be the Hierarchy.
The Hierarchy?
There are two factions of Highlanders.
One is the Grand Duchy.
They give us not only Artifacts, but also
Flying Gears and other new technology.
The other is the Hierarchy.
They prefer to keep new technology from
those of us on the surface whenever possible.
Each of these two large factions
would send Hyral Menases to each country
to maintain the balance of power.
But that balance is collapsing.
Ripple is a Hyral Menas
created by the Hierarchy.
They may have prepared a way
to destroy her from within.
So Ripple's just a toy
in your power struggles?
Eris...
She offered herself up to become a
Hyral Menas and protect the surface.
But...
the Highland... the Highlanders...
are doing this to her?
Why are we even here?
To protect, I think.
You protected me.
And I'm glad we have the Flying Gears, too!
We can get to people who are far away faster
and protect them from the magicite beasts!
You...
Rafinha's right, isn't she, Inglis?
Yes. I like it that way,
because I get to fight more.
No, that's not what I meant...
I'm sorry for speaking out of turn.
No, it's better to think the way that you do.
I'll do my best to bring
Ripple back to normal.
Thank you.
And I need to thank you, too.
For speaking up back there. Thank you.
Of course!
It was a pure-hearted and honest opinion.
You're not only beautiful on the outside,
but you have a beautiful heart, too.
N-No, I...
"Beautiful?"
I've never seen Rani like this before.
Perhaps I've finally found
the boy I need to drive off!
Would you tell me your name?
This is Rafinha Bilford.
The younger sister of
Holy Knight Rafael over there.
I'm Inglis Eucus, her squire.
Hey, Chris! What's gotten into you?
I'm just doing what a squire should!
Rafinha? Inglis?
So you're the ones who
saved my little sister?
Sister?
Seilyn is my little sister.
I heard she was turned
into a magicite beast.
Where is she now?
Right here.
Seilyn?
It's small, but yes, I can feel her mana.
I'm sorry. All we could do
was save her in this state.
No, you did well.
I'll find a way to turn her back.
Theodore...
I'll take her, then.
Of course.
Seilyn, you're safe now!
Ouch!
What's wrong, Seilyn?
Lyn, your brother's here for you!
Lyn, that tickles!
Chris, don't move. I'll pull her out!
No! Rani!
Maybe she doesn't want to go back?
It feels like she's different
from the Seilyn I knew.
Maybe I should leave her
in your care for now.
All right.
That's fine with us.
Theodore, Ripple has...
She's awake?!
Whew...
Are you okay?
For now.
But I remember what happened, a little.
I hurt everyone... I'm sorry.
It's not your fault.
That's right.
Thanks, you guys.
But I can't take this anymore...
I'm not sure why I even
became a Hyral Menas.
Listen, Wein. If you can't find a way
to stop this, go ahead and destroy me.
Or throw me away somewhere
where nobody else is around.
Never!
We could never do that to the
woman who protects our country!
This won't go on for much longer.
Just rest someplace that's well guarded.
I'll find a place for her right away.
And I'll post guards to protect her.
Thanks.
Excuse me.
I have a suggestion...
Go ahead and say it.
Why not bring her to the knights' academy?
The knights' academy?
Losing Ripple will already be
a big hit to the knights' strength.
And if you have to assign people
to guard her, you'll lose even more strength.
That should be avoided, I think.
So we have someone besides the knights
protect her, to help keep the nation safe?
That's a great idea, Chris!
We can keep Ripple safe ourselves!
I'm against this.
The academy is in the middle of a city.
If the magicite beasts get out, it will
put the people of the capital in danger.
If I may speak, too...
If we want to find out why this happened,
we'll need Miliera's help.
Which means...
It would be best to have her at the academy,
where my lab is located.
Ripple is feeling guilty right now.
So we'll defeat all the
magicite beasts she summons
without any of us getting hurt
or putting the townspeople in danger.
Then she won't feel so bad.
I want to protect her heart, as well.
Inglis...
I like that!
"Protect her heart!"
Thanks...
I've decided to put my faith in your resolve
and leave her in the academy's care.
Miliera, I entrust the rest to you.
Of course, Your Highness.
Theodore, please do what you can
to assist them, too.
We'll get to the bottom of this. I promise.
Thanks, everyone.
Right!
I didn't realize Inglis cared so much.
You're always seeing the best in people, huh?
Being around Ripple will give her
more chances to fight magicite beasts.
You don't think that's what she was thinking?
Maybe that's it...
m 506 97 l 609 99 611 247 516 302 488 145
Eris would
look great
with animal
ears, too!
Meow!
Woof!
A matching pair!
Comic by Kuromura Moto